<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<faqs>

<faq>
<title>What is PB Tracker?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
PB Tracker is a web app for tracking <a href=http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speedrun>speedrunning</a> times, personal bests (PBs) and viewing other runner's PBs. 
Runners sign up and submit their times to populate their very own personal runner page. 
This runner page is the main feature of PB Tracker, providing a useful reference point for looking up a runner's best times. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Is there a banner for PB Tracker that I can use on my Twitch TV channel?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
Yes there is! 
Funny you should ask. 
It's nothing special, but this <a href="http://imgur.com/gkz47Ch">simple PB Tracker banner</a> should do the trick. 
Be sure to link the banner image to your runner page.
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>I cannot find game X and category Y on PB Tracker. Where is it?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
While PB Tracker does contain a healthy database of games and run categories, not every game and category is listed. 
However, users may submit times for any game and category they wish. 
If the game or category does not exist, PB Tracker will create a page for the game and add the category to the database. 
So, feel free to add run times to any games and categories you wish!
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>I made a mistake when I submitted a run.  How can I fix it?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
When logged in, head to your runner page by clicking on your username in the top navigation bar. 
From there, there will be a list icon in the top left just above your PB table.
Clicking this icon will bring up a list of all of your runs, sorted by date. 
Find the run you wish to edit or delete and click the appropriate icon in the far right column of the table. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>How does auto-submission with Time Split Tracker work?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="https://forum.speeddemosarchive.com/post/timerstopwatch_program_377.html#timerstopwatch_program_377">Time Split Tracker</a> is a splits program by <a href="https://twitter.com/dunnius">dunnius</a> for speedrunning and is a useful tool to keep track of level completion times during a run. 
Time Split Tracker supports auto-submission of runs to PB Tracker. 
To enable this feature, click options and go down to enable auto-upload. 
Enter your credentials and the game info on the menu that pops up. 
Note that new games and categories currently cannot be auto-submitted and the first run of a new game or category must be submitted manually on the web. 
Once enabled, on completion of a run (after the final split is hit), your run time will be automatically submitted to PB Tracker. 
If a mistake was made in the auto-submitted time (such as the final split was hit too late), you may always edit your runs from your list / edit runs page. 
Note that the date of the run will be the current day in UTC unless you update your time zone information on your edit profile page. 
</p>
<p>
Here are some useful tips for getting started with Time Split Tracker:
<ol>
<li>Download <a href="https://forum.speeddemosarchive.com/post/timerstopwatch_program_377.html#timerstopwatch_program_377">Time Split Tracker</a> and extract the files to a local directory.</li>
<li>For basic splits, copy and rename the "Sample No Comparison Times.txt" file to something more appropriate (such as "mega-man-2.txt").</li>
<li>Open the Time Split Tracker executable, go to "Open splits," and select your new file.</li>
<li>Right-click on various parts of the Time Split Tracker window to bring up contextual menus and edit the appropriate labels, add or remove split rows, change row images, etc.</li>
<li>Go to Options -> Enable auto-upload, select PB Tracker as the server, and enter the appropriate information.</li>
<li>Finally, Time Split Tracker offers several advanced features, including comparison against multiple split columns.  If you prefer a simpler, single column of splits, you can edit your preferences yourself or download <a href="/static/time-split-tracker.ini" download="Time Split Tracker.ini">this configuration file</a> and overwrite the existing file in your Time Split Tracker directory.</li>
</ol>
</p>
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Isn't there a blog about PB Tracker?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
Yes there is! 
You can find it at <a href="http://richardggibson.appspot.com/blog">http://richardggibson.appspot.com/blog</a>.
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>How can I request a feature or report a problem?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
You can send an <a href="mailto:[name-of-site-no-spaces]speedruns[AT]gmail[DOT]com">email</a> or contact <a href="https://twitter.com/rggibson_">rggibson</a> on Twitter. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Some of the games and categories are mislabelled and thus are not merged properly.  How can this be fixed?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
You can let <a href="https://twitter.com/rggibson_">rggibson</a> know of any problems like this that you find.  
However, a better approach might be to send a friendly message to the runner if you believe they have mislabelled a game or category and ask them to edit their run. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>How can I contribute?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
The code for PB Tracker is open-source, so anyone is welcome to work on the site. 
Check out the <a href="https://github.com/rggibson/pb-tracker/issues?direction=asc&sort=created&state=open">issues</a> and let <a href="https://twitter.com/rggibson_">rggibson</a> know if you want to work on any of them. 
He is happy to take pull requests from anyone willing to put in the time to come up with a workable solution. 
If you have a feature that you want to work on for PB Tracker and it is not listed on the issues page, <a href="mailto:[name-of-site-no-spaces]speedruns[AT]gmail[DOT]com">drop us a line</a> to make sure that it is a suitable feature for PB Tracker.
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Where is the box art for game X?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
While we are trying to keep up with all of the games being added to PB Tracker, sometimes the box art for certain games are missing, particularly games recently added. 
In fact, the easiest way that you can help contribute to the site is to add the box art images to the /static/boxart/ directory in the <a href="https://github.com/rggibson/pb-tracker">open-source GitHub repository</a> and send a <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/fork-a-repo">pull request</a>. 
Make sure the box art image filename is [game_code].jpg, where http://www.pbtracker.net/game/[game_code] is the URL for the game page. 
]]></content>
</faq>

</faqs>
