<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<faqs>

<faq>
<title>What is PB Tracker?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
PB Tracker is a web app for tracking <a href=http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speedrun>speedrunning</a> times, personal bests (PBs) and viewing other runner's PBs. 
Runners sign up and submit their times to populate their very own personal runner page. 
This runner page is the main feature of PB Tracker, providing a useful reference point for looking up a runner's best times. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>I cannot find game X and category Y on PB Tracker. Where is it?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
While PB Tracker does contain a healthy database of games and run categories, not every game and category is listed. 
However, users may submit times for any game and category they wish. 
If the game or category does not exist, PB Tracker will create a page for the game and add the category to the database. 
So, feel free to add run times to any games and categories you wish!
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>I made a mistake when I submitted a run.  How can I fix it?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
When logged in, head to your runner page by clicking on your username in the top navigation bar. 
From there, there will be a link to view and edit your runs. 
This will bring up a table of all of your runs, sorted by date. 
Find the run you wish to edit or delete and click the appropriate icon in the far right column of the table. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Isn't there a blog about PB Tracker?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
Yes there is! 
You can find it at <a href="http://richardggibson.appspot.com/blog">http://richardggibson.appspot.com/blog</a>.
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>How can I request a feature or report a problem?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
You can send an <a href="mailto:[name-of-site-no-spaces]speedruns[AT]gmail[DOT]com">email</a> or contact <a href="https://twitter.com/rggibson_">@rggibson_</a> on Twitter. 
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>How can I contribute?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
The code for PB Tracker is open-source, so anyone is welcome to work on the site. 
Check out the <a href="https://github.com/rggibson/pb-tracker/issues?direction=asc&sort=created&state=open">issues</a> and let <a href="https://twitter.com/rggibson_">rggibson</a> know if you want to work on any of them. 
He is happy to take pull requests from anyone willing to put in the time to come up with a workable solution. 
If you have a feature that you want to work on for PB Tracker and it is not listed on the issues page, <a href="mailto:[name-of-site-no-spaces]speedruns[AT]gmail[DOT]com">drop us a line</a> to make sure that it is a suitable feature for PB Tracker.
]]></content>
</faq>

<faq>
<title>Where is the box art for game X?</title>
<content><![CDATA[
While we are trying to keep up with all of the games being added to PB Tracker, sometimes the box art for certain games are missing, particularly games recently added. 
In fact, the easiest way that you can help contribute to the site is to add the box art images to the /static/boxart/ directory in the <a href="https://github.com/rggibson/pb-tracker">open-source GitHub repository</a> and send a pull request. 
Make sure the box art image filename is [game_code].jpg, where http://www.pbtracker.net/game/[game_code] is the URL for the game page. 
]]></content>
</faq>

</faqs>
